<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rashad is here to fulfill all of your Software engineering & Design needs.]]></description><link>https://rashadmadison.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 22:42:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Whats A Domain Name?]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Importance of a Domain Name A domain name is the first step to getting your website started. For many, the process begins with a clear…]]></description><link>https://rashadmadison.com/rashadsblog/domainname/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rashadmadison.com/rashadsblog/domainname/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;The Importance of a Domain Name&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A domain name is the first step to getting your website started. For many, the process begins with a clear idea of the perfect name—until they discover it&apos;s unavailable. Often, people treat domain names like other online accounts, simply adding a number or settling for whatever the registrar suggests. For instance, if &quot;love.com&quot; isn’t available, they might opt for &quot;love123.com&quot; or &quot;love-happy.net.&quot; But your domain name is more than just a URL—it’s a critical investment in your brand and online presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While securing a domain name can be affordable, finding the perfect name for your business requires thoughtful consideration of your brand, competition, SEO, and customer needs. Your domain name is how customers find you, and in some cases, how your competitors could capture your customers if you’re not strategic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creativity Matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 98.95833333333334%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot; &gt; &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/ZtOa0Ko8WYoHtVIwnK&quot; style=&quot; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/babybluecat-cocofofo-think-outside-the-box-ZtOa0Ko8WYoHtVIwnK&quot;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/television-90s-XjGC8GC1Y8ILe&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing out with a memorable domain name is essential. Unfortunately, many people rush this step because they’re in a hurry to secure any available name. It’s true that domain names are commodities, and once someone else buys a name, it’s theirs. Like real estate, the value of a domain often increases over time. A domain name purchased for $12 today could be worth thousands of dollars in just a few years, especially if it generates traffic and adds value to its user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 100%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot; &gt; &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/7oIn6Khh0sF3r4qQdW&quot; style=&quot; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/JustStartInvesting-7oIn6Khh0sF3r4qQdW&quot;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Understanding Top-Level Domains (TLDs)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get a little technical. Every domain has a Top-Level Domain (TLD), such as .com, .org, or .net. The TLD helps categorize the site. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.org is ideal for nonprofits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.com is widely recognized and associated with commerce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.shop or other niche TLDs can communicate specific purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a full list of TLD options, check out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Internet_top-level_domains&quot;&gt;resource&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security and Choosing the Right Registrar
Unfortunately, domain names can be exploited by bad actors. To avoid issues, choose a reputable registrar to secure your domain. Doing so not only ensures proper security but also safeguards your investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Thoughts
Selecting the right domain name involves more than just creativity—it requires strategic thinking about SEO, branding, and security. If you’d like to dive deeper into this topic, feel free to connect with me and learn more &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;rashadmad@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[So What Have I Been Up To Hello, I'm Rashad I'm a passionate developer with strong design skills. I have decided to start journaling my…]]></description><link>https://rashadmadison.com/rashadsblog/helloworld/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://rashadmadison.com/rashadsblog/helloworld/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;So What Have I Been Up To&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, I&apos;m Rashad I&apos;m a passionate developer with strong design skills. I have decided to start journaling my experiences as an engineer and creator. I think I have a non-traditional path to the world of engineering. I have some crazy stories to tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I lost my job with JPMorgan Chase after almost three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It always sucks to connect with folks, figure out ways to contribute to a team and have to start over. On the other hand developing one&apos;s self and taking on new challenges are exciting and essential for keeping rust from forming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I Can Help Your Business GROWWWW&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 62.06896551724138%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden; margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot; &gt; &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/XjGC8GC1Y8ILe&quot; style=&quot; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/television-90s-XjGC8GC1Y8ILe&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am taking this time to connect with small business and assisting them in developing there online brand. Freelancing can be challenging but I love working with people and assiting them in chasing there dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since losing my job, I have been reflecting on my career path and considering this as an opportunity to steer my career in the direction it should go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logos are powerful building blocks for your online brand. I create logos that look great on t-shirts and on social media profiles. The key is design with vectors. Vector logo designed professionally are future proof and can go any where and still look good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my logo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://rashad-madison-images.s3.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/rashad_logo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tailor Made &amp;#x26; Bespoke Designs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I designed my logo to be a kind of mascot that l can be trusted with there technology needs. Though my logo is very stylized I am capable of many types of designs and can create a logo for you that is tailored to you and your clients needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have interest in developing a 3D version of this soon keep and eye out for that. 3D is a powerful way to communicate a strong and professional brand. I plan on doing a future blog post showing how I go about developing 3D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1517292987719-0369a794ec0f?q=80&amp;amp;w=4074&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;amp;ixid=M3wxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8fA%3D%3D&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: 0 auto&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks for checking me out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am quite excited about the new website you are visiting right now. Thank you for showing interest in me and my work. I consider myself a pretty interesting individual with plenty to share. I look forward to sharing my musings and works in progress with you. If you are in need of a software engineer and artist, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>